American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIg. 1887-1891 APS.Archives.IIg APS.Archives.IIg
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Oct. 21, 1891; 7x4-1/2; Jastrow, Joseph, 1863-1944
    Madison, Wis., A.L.S. 2p., end., and end. Inquires about copies of Mesmer's Précis historique des faits relatifs au magnétisme-animal, presented to A.P.S. through Franklin.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Oct. 21, 1891; 8x5; Pilling, James Constantine, 1846-1895
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p., end. Inquires about section of library catalogue on N.A. Indians. Refers to A.S. Gatschet. Asks about exchange of duplicates.
  - Letter to Paul Leicester Ford, Oct. 22, 1891; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Photo. of T.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 26, 1891; 8x5; Pilling, James Constantine, 1846-1895
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Asks for copy of library catalogue.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 29, 1891; 8x5; Pilling, James Constantine, 1846-1895
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., end. Acknowledges receipt of catalogue.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Oct. 30, 1891; 9x5-3/4; Knapp, Arthur Mason, 1839-1898
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p., end. Is preparing Catalogue of Franklin portraits. Asks for information on Martin Portrait.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Oct. 31, 1891; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Concerns report of committee on publication of the Proceedings.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, [Oct., 1891]; Ford, Paul Leicester, 1865-1902
    Photo of A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Nov. 2, 1891; 11x8; Perry, Charles M.
    Saltville, Va., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about papers by J.P. Lesley on the geology of Virginia.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., Nov. 4, 1891; 7x4-1/2; Sheardown, Annie Fillmore
    Atlanta, Ga., A.L.S. 4p. and add., end. Pupil of Emma Seiler. Asks to join A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 4, 1891; 11x8-1/4; New York (N.Y.). Committee on Centennial Celebration of the Inauguration of Washington, 1789
    New York, Typed L.S.: Clarence W. Bowen, Secretary. 1p., end. Asks for information on Peale-Martin portrait of Franklin.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, Nov. 6, 1891; 9x5-1/2; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns withdrawal of Peale Stone Age collection from deposit at Academy of Natural Sciences.
    Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 8, 1891; 11x8-1/2; South Dakota. Agricultural Experiment Station
    Brookings, S.D., Typed L.S.: Luther Foster, Director. 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to J[ames] C[heston] Morris, Nov. 13, 1891; 9x5-1/2; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. Concerns Peale Stone Age collection. Encloses copy of part of Caroline Peale's will regarding the collection which may assist Curators. For enclosure, see Caroline E.G. Peale, Extract from will proved at Phila., Oct. 12, 1875.
  - Letter to Henry Philips [sic], Nov. 14, 1891; 8x7; Bonwill, William Gibson Arlington, 1833-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. 4p., end., and add., end. Concerns his paper on evolution. Will read it whenever assigned a time.
  - Letter to [William Gibson Arlington] Bonwill, Nov. 15, 1891; 9x5-3/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., L. 2p. Draft. Explains why Bonwill's paper on evolution was not published in the Proceedings.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Nov. 19, 1891; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Diplomas are signed, ready to be sent.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Nov. 27, 1891; 13x8-3/4; Buenos Aires (Argentina: Province). Direccíon General de Estadística
    La Plata, L.S.: Julio N. Rosas, Directeur Géneral. 2p., end. In French. Has succeeded Adolfo Montier as Director
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 28, 1891; 11x8-1/4; New York (N.Y.). Committee on Centennial Celebration of the Inauguration of Washington, 1789
    New York, Typed L.S.: Clarence W. Bowen, Secretary. 1p., end. Requests permission to photograph the Houdon bust of Franklin.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 30, 1891; 11x8-1/4; New York (N.Y.). Committee on Centennial Celebration of the Inauguration of Washington, 1789
    New York. Typed L.S.: Clarence W. Bowen, Secretary. 1p., end. Asks to compare print of Franklin bust owned by C. Abert with the Houdon bust of Franklin.
  - Letter to [Mississippi agricultural & mechanical college], Nov., 1891; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Printed L. 1p., end. by S[amuel] M[ills] Tracy Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov., 1891; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Oaxaca. Museo
    Oaxaco, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. In French Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., Dec. 1, 1891; 12x8; Ethnikon Asteroskopeion Athēnōn
    Athens, Greece, Printed L. with MS. additions. 1p., end. Concerns exchange of meteorological publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 2, 1891; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Wagner, Samuel, 1842-
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends his photograph.
  - Letter to Henry Philips [sic], Dec. 5, 1891; 3x5; Bonwill, William Gibson Arlington, 1833-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Postpones reading his paper on evolution until early 1892.
  - Letter to James G[illespie] Blaine, Secretary of State, Dec. 8, 1891; 10x8; France. Légation (U.S.)
    Washington, L.S.: P. Desprez. 1p., end. Copy [by Phillips?] Announces Carlier bequest to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 8, 1891; 11x8-1/4; New York (N.Y.). Committee on Centennial Celebration of the Inauguration of Washington, 1789
    New York, Typed L.S.: Clarence W. Bowen, Secretary. 1p. Asks permission to photograph the Martin bust of Franklin.
  - Letter to Henry Philips sic, Dec. 9, 1891; 3x5; Bonwill, William Gibson Arlington, 1833-1899
    [Phila. A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add Accepts Feb. 5, 1892, as date to read his paper, "Geometry and Mechanics Deny Evolution."]
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 10, 1891; 10-1/4x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, L.S.: James G[illespie] Blaine. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends note from French legation announcing Carlier bequest to A.P.S. For copy of note, see France. Legation. U.S. to J.G. Blaine, Dec. 8, 1891.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 11, 1891; 11x8-3/4; Bowdoin College
    Brunswick, Maine, A.L.S.: Geo. T. Little, Libn. 1p. Enc. wanting. Asks for exchange of publications. Sends list of Bowdoin publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 11, 1891; 11x8-1/4; New York (N.Y.). Committee on Centennial Celebration of the Inauguration of Washington, 1789
    New York, Typed L.S.: Clarence W. Bowen, Secretary. 1p. Asks permission to photograph the Peale-Martin portrait of Franklin.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Dec. 14, 1891; 8-1/2x5-1/2; American Museum of Natural History
    N.Y., A.L.S.: A. Woodward, Librarian. 1p., end. and end. Concerns exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Dec. 14, 1891; 9x5-3/4; Bowdoin College
    Brunswick, Maine, A.L.S.: Geo[rge] T. Little [Librarian]. 1p., end., and end. Concerns its set of A.P.S. Proceedings.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Dec. 15, 1891; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Gatschet, Albert S. (Albert Samuel), 1832-1907
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., end., and end. Concerns his paper, "A Mythic Tale of the Isleta Indians." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 29, pp.208-218.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Dec. 21, 1891; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Gatschet, Albert S. (Albert Samuel), 1832-1907
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Concerns printing of his paper, "A Mythic Tale of Isleta." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings. vol. 29, pp.208-218.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Dec. 26, 1891; 8x5; Hill, A. J. (Alfred James), 1833-1895
    St. Paul, Minn., A.L.S. 4p. Inquires about maps in the Lewis and Clark diaries, in connection with his interest in historical geography of the North West.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Dec. 29, 1891; 8x5; New York Mathematical Society
    New York, A.L.S.: Thomas S. Fiske, Secy. 2p., end. Asks for copy of A.B. Taylor's paper on octonary numeration for Gustav Eneström of Stockholm.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, [1891]; 8x5-1/4; Cattell, William C. (William Cassaday), 1827-1898
    [Phila.], Monday A.L.S. 1p., end., and end. Refers to his election as a Councillor of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, 1891?; 11x8-1/2; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.,] A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns reading of his paper on "Possible Sterilization of City Water." For printed paper, see: A.P.S. Proceedings, Vol. 29, pp.26-39.
  - Letter to George H[enry] Horn, 1891; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Hael, George Walter
    New York, Mimeo. L. with MS. additions. 3p. Concerns his opinion on meteors.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, [1891]; 7x4-1/2; Smyth, Albert Henry, 1863-1907
    [Phila.], Monday A.L.S. 3p. and end. Recommends Isidore Schwab for work in A.P.S. Library.